Mario Pereira

Full Stack Developer

nikhilpereira125@gmail.com | 647-668-7184 | linkedin.com/in/nikhilpereira25/ | nmpereira.com

Summary

Software engineer with experience in frontend and backend development, cloud infrastructure, project management. With a strong background in QA testing, excelling at building well tested, scalable and efficient software solutions using MongoDB, Express, Node, React, Python and Typescript.

Technical Skills

Languages

JavaScript (JS), TypeScript (TS), Python

Frontend

React, EJS, TailwindCSS, Nextjs, styled-components

Backend

Express, Node, Websockets, WebRTC, Flask, Cloud functions

Databases

MongoDB, PSQL, Redis, ConvexDB

Testing

Cypress, Jest, Postman, Puppeteer, Selenium

DevOps

Git, Perforce, EC2, Netlify, Vercel, Github Actions, CI/CD

Work Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer

Paystone | Aug 2022 - Apr 2023

- Spearheaded Cypress E2E testing implementation for the Paystone app, testing key workflows to enhance quality assurance
- Led and successfully executed a major initiative to modernize a legacy reporting dashboard by migrating it to a new platform using React and styled-components.
- Led the application reskinning during a rebranding effort, showcasing creativity and adaptability.
- Enhanced React components for improved logic, functionality, performance, and user experience.
- Played a pivotal role in updating and improving legacy payments code and developing tools for on-call engineers.
- Advocated for the improvement of Cypress in the development workflow, enhancing maintenance and usage.
- Demonstrated an acute eye for detail by identifying and resolving 30+ UI bugs through Cypress UI testing.
- Utilized MongoDB, TypeScript, AWS/GCP cloud functions & App engine routes, React, styled-components, Cypress, and Jest.

Software Developer

Intuit | Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Drove a 40% improvement in productivity, through the development of a utility software that completely automated a manual process performed by 10 -15 team members daily.
- Led an effort to revamp an internal tool using React and PDFjs for tax form creation that significantly improved tax form creation time by 60%.
- Automated QA 50+ testcases, resulting in a 30% reduction in testing time/manual QA.
- Troubleshot software payload errors using Jenkins and Splunk, ensuring software integrity.

Application Support Specialist

InsideDesk | Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Implemented automation of processes using Google Apps Script, Selenium/Python, and Power Automate, resulting in substantial time savings for staff.
- Enhanced workflow efficiency by developing software connectors/APIs, automating the flow of insurance claim information.
- Addressed bugs and user feedback adeptly using relevant tools.

Quality Assurance / Tax Forms Specialist,

Intuit | Aug 2019 - Oct 2021

- Contributed to the creation of the ProTax filing suite, involving tax research, algorithm implementation, bug identification, and software quality assurance.
- Cataloged and updated over 400+ tax forms for tax years 2019, 2020 and 2021.
- Created and documented over 700+ manual QA workflows/test cases to test all major tax forms in predictable manner.

Projects

Communityfocus

- Led a group project that rebuilt TimeShare (shared timer for remote teams) with a revamped UI and improved features.
- Skills gained: Mentoring, Code reviews, Issue writing, project management, advanced React/Typescript.
- Stack: React, TypeScript, MongoDB, Expressis, Socket.io and styled-components.
- Link: communityfocus.app | github.com/CommunityFocus

100Editors

- Built a shared text editor game for a hackathon where users type a story based on validation rules.
- Skills gained: Development under pressure, Collaborative coding, Data validation.
- Stack: Nextjs, React, TailwindCSS, WebRTC, Quill and Yjs.
- Link: 100editors.vercel.app | github.com/web-dev-cody-hackathon/100editors

PriceDashBoard

- Developed a price comparison dashboard that uses WebCrawlers to get the price of products and reports to the user to compare between different stores.
- Skills gained: Webcrawling with puppeteer/Axios, React, DaisyUI (CSS), caching, MongoDB full-text search.
- Stack: Puppeteer, Typescript, Express, MongoDB, and React, Tailwind/DaisyUI CSS.
- Link: cannabis-price.nmpereira.com | github.com/nmpereira/prettydakush

ConvoCards

- Created a Conversation Card game where uses can play the deck using user submitted card prompts.
- Skills gained: Integrating Auth0, Tailwind, DaisyUI,
- Stack: Express, EJS, Tailwind / DaisyUI CSS, Auth0 and MongoDB.
- Link: <u>cards.nmpereira.com</u> | <u>github.com/nmpereira/cardGameBackend</u>

TimeShare

- Built a shared pomodoro timer for remote teams.
- Skills gained: Websockets/Socket.io, Express, EJS, Bootstrap.
- Stack: Express, Node, MongoDB, and Socket.io.
- Link: vulture.nmpereira.com | github.com/nmpereira/time-share

Education

- Bachelors in Business Administration (BBA), University of Toronto (2019)
- Full Stack Software Development, 100Devs Bootcamp (2021)